Guide to the Edward Lee Plumb Papers, 1856-1912
Department of Special Collections
- CORRESPONDENCE 1867, May - August (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 21. 1867, July 3.William H. Seward to E.L. Plumb., N.S.
  - 22. 1867, July 9.J. Edgar Thomson to E.L. Plumb. Plumb applying for post of Minister to Mexico., A.L.S.
  - 23. 1867, July 15.Caleb Cushing to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 24. 1867, July 18.George Wilkes to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 25. 1867, July 19.Charles Sumner to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 26. 1867, July 22.E.L. Plumb to William H. Seward., A.L.S. (not sent).
  - 27. 1867, July 26.Felipe B. Berriozabal to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S. in Spanish.
  - 28. 1867, July 28.Benito Juarez to E.L. Plumb. Announces return to Mexico City., L.S. in Spanish.
  - 29. 1867, July 28.Pedro [Santacilia] to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S. in Spanish.
  - 30. 1867, Aug. 6.R.B. Gorsueh to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 31. 1867, Aug. 15.William H. Seward to Sebastian Lerdo de Tejada. E.L. Plumb Chargé d'Affaires ad interim in Mexico., L. (copy).
  - 32. 1867, Aug. 14.Charles Sumner to [E.L. Plumb?]., A.L.S.
  - 33. 1867, Aug. 18.Charles Sumner to [E.L. Plumb?]., A.L.S.
  - 34. 1867, Aug. 19.W. Hunter to E.L. Plumb. Inquiry after Maximilian's put. sec. & Belgian Chargé d'Affaires., A.L.S.
  - 35. 1867, Aug. 19.M. Jordan to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 36. 1867, Aug. 20.F. von Gerolt to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 37. 1867, Aug. 26.Sam Warde to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 38. 1867, Aug. 27.Sam Warde to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 39. 1867, Aug. 31.W. Hunter to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
- CORRESPONDENCE 1867, September - December (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 1. 1867, [Sep. 2?].W.F. Buckley to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 2. 1867, Sep. 2.M.O. Davidson to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 3. 1867, [Sep. 2?].J.M. Witherspoon to W.F. Buckley., A.L.S.
  - 4. 1867, Sep. 11.George E. Church to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 5. 1867, Sep. 11.M. Romero to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 6. 1867, Sep. 12.M. de Embril to Plumb., L.S.
  - 7. 1867, Sep. 16.G.R. Ruthven to Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 8. 1867, Sep. 25.F. von Gerolt to Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 9. 1867, Oct. 1.Thomas Savage to Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 10. 1867, Oct. 7.W.T. Sherman to Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 11. 1867, Oct. 9.in Spanish. P. de Baranda to Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 12. 1867, Oct. 9.E. H. Saulnier to E.L. Plumb., Tel. in Spanish.
  - 13. 1867, Oct. 10.George E. Church to Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 14. 1867, Oct. 10.in Spanish. Ramon S. Diaz to Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 15. 1867, Oct. 10.Philip Sheridan to E.L. Plumb., [A.L.S.?].
  - 16. 1867, Oct. 11.Francis [DeGrese] to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 17. 1867, Oct. 16.Caleb Cushing to Plumb., L.S.
  - 18. 1867, Oct. 21.R. von Magnus to Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 19. 1867, Oct. 23.[B.H. Cheerer] to Plumb. American & Mexican RR & Telegraph Co., A.L.S.
  - 20. 1867, Oct. 23.A. [Edw.] G. de Lascurain to E.L. Plumb., A.N.S.
  - 21. 1867, Oct. 26.Ira Harris to Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 22. 1867, Oct. 29.A. Farine to E.L. Plumb; copy in Fr. July 10 Marcus Otterbourg to [E.L. Plumb]; Oct. 31E.L. Plumb to A. Farine., A.L.S. L. (copy) in French.
  - 23. 1867, Oct. 31.Caleb Cushing to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 24. 1867, Nov. 5.J.C. Bancroft Davis to [E.L. Plumb]. Plumb resigns., A.L.S.
  - 25. 1867, Nov. 6.R. von Magnus to E.L. Plumb. Prince Salm Salm & rank of general., A.L.S.
  - 26. 1867, Nov. 7.M. Romero to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 27. 1867, Nov. 13.[F. Eloin] to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S. in French.
  - 28. 1867, Nov. 14.F. von Gerolt to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 29. 1867, Nov. 15.Geo. W. Hogan to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 30. 1867, Nov. 15.J.R. West to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 31. 1867, Nov. 23.[Thomas] Savage to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 32. 1867, Nov. 28.[H.T.C.] Middletown to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 33. 1867, Nov. 29.A. Grant to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 34. 1867, Nov. 30.Chas. W. Davis to E.L. Plumb. Impeachment likely to fail., A.L.S.
  - 35. 1867, Nov. 30.[H.T.C.] Middleton to Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 36. 1867, Dec. 2.W.A. Corbiere to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 37. 1867, Dec. 7.Wm. F. Buckley to E.L. Plumb. Business climate and events in New York., A.L.S.
  - 38. 1867, Dec. 7.O.J. Degollado to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 39. 1867, Dec. 7.F.D. Macin to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 40. 1867, Dec. 9.A. Jouan to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 41. 1867, Dec. 9.H.T.C. Middleton to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 42. 1867, Dec. 14.George B. Crawley to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 43. 1867, Dec. 23.H.R. de la Remitrie to E.L. Plumb. Impeachment; shipwreck., A.L.S.
- CORRESPONDENCE 1868, January-March (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 1. 1868, Jan. 11.F. von Gerolt to E.L. Plumb. Aid for Maximilian's partisans., A.L.S.
  - 2. 1868, Jan. 15.J.M. Mata to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 3. 1868, Jan. 15.M. Romero to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 4. 1868, Jan. 22.M. Romero to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 5. 1868, Jan 24.M. Romero to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 6. 1868, Jan. 26.Anita de Chase to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 7. 1868, Jan.T.H. Worrall to E.L. Plumb. Position of minister to Mexico, etc., A.L.S.
  - 8. 1868, Feb. 6.David Hoadley to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 9. 1868, Feb. 7.Herman Sturm to M. Romero. Mentions draft of Placida Vega., A.L.S.
  - 10. 1868, Feb. 7.Herman Sturm to Sebastian Lerdo de Tejada., A.L.S.
  - 11-12. 1868, Feb. 8.S. Lerdo de Tejada to Herman Sturm., [2 A.L.S. or copies in Spanish?]
  - 13. 1868, Feb. 9.S. Lerdo de Tejada to Herman Sturm., Note in Spanish.
  - 14. 1868, Feb. 10.Herman Sturm to S. Lerdo de Tejada with note to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 15. 1868, Feb 12,R.G. Guzman to E.L. Plumb., L.S. in Spanish
  - 16. 1868, Feb 12Lerdo de Tejada to [Herman Sturm]., [L. copy in Spanish]
  - 17. 1868, Feb 12,Lerdo de Tejada to [Herman Sturm]., [L. copy in Spanish]
  - 18. 1868, Feb 12,M. Romero to Herman Sturm., copy in Spanish
  - 19. 1868, Feb 13,Jesus Cartanada to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S. in Spanish
  - 20. 1868, Feb 17.J.A. Gamboa to Herman Sturm., Copy in Spanish
  - 21. 1868, Feb 18.Herman Sturm to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 22. 1868, Feb 20.Martin Mayoso (Pres. Sociedad de Beneficeneia Espanola) to E.L. Plumb., A.N.S. in Spanish
  - 23. 1868, Feb 22.P.de Baranda to E.L. Plumb., A.N.S. in Spanish
  - 24. 1868, Feb 24.H.R. de la Remitrie to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 25. 1868, Feb 24.Kane O'Donnel to E.L. Plumb., A.N.S.
  - 26. 1868, Feb 25.O.E. Babcock to E.L. Plumb. Impeachment, thinks Johnson is crazy., A.L.S.
  - 27-28. 1868, Feb 25.R.C. McCormick to E.L. Plumb. Arizona and Sonora, Apaches., 2 A.L.S.
  - 29. 1868, Feb 29.Luis N. de la Lastray Bonille to E.L. Plumb., A.N. in Spanish.
  - 30. 1868, Mar 7.N. Davidson to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 31. 1868, Mar 7.J.F. Uhink to E.L. Plumb., A.N.S.
  - 32. 1868, Mar 8.Estanislao Cañedo to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 33. 1868, Mar 16.Estaban Benecke to E.L. Plumb., A.N.
  - 34. 1868, Mar 23.Sister Estefamia for Sisters of Charity to [E.L. Plumb.], A.L.S. in Spanish.
  - 35. 1868, Mar 29.William Barron to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 36. 1868, Mar 29.M. Romero to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
- CORRESPONDENCE 1868, April-December (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - 1. 1868, Apr 1.Ramon Iglesial to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S. in Spanish.
  - 2. 1868, Apr 2.B.H. Cheerer to E.L. Plumb. Railroad., A.L.S.
  - 3. 1868, Apr 11.E. Cañeda to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 4. 1868, Apr 12.F. von Gerolt to E.L. Plumb. Impeachment; Mexico's refusal of British minister., A.L.S.
  - 5. 1868, Apr 22.Francis Fesser to E. L. Plumb., A.L.S. in Spanish.
  - 6. 1868, Apr 24.O.E. Babcock to E.L. Plumb. Candidates, impeachment, Mexican debt., A.L.S.
  - 7. 1868, Apr 25.John Black to E.L. Plumb., A.N.S.
  - 8. 1868, Apr 30.F. de Lezarde to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 9. 1868, Apr 30.A.H. Plumb to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 10. 1868, May 20. American Claims Against Mexico. Reprint from N.Y. Herald., Ptd. art. & cvr. letter-
  - 11. 1868, May 28.Esteban Benecke to E.L. Plumb. Aquital of Johnson., A.L.S.
  - 12. 1868, June 6.W.P. Blake to E.L. Plumb. Precious metals., A.L.S.
  - 13. 1868, June 27.Duncan, Sherman & Co. to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 14. 1868, July 1.O.E. Babcock to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 15. 1868, July 4.Francisco de [P. Pastor] to E.L. Plumb., A.L. in Spanish.
  - 16. 1868, July 12.F.B. Elmer to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 17. 1868, July 14.N. Davidson to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 18. 1868, July 18.Ramon Guzman and Jesus Castaneda to E.L. Plumb., A.N. in Spanish.
  - 19. 1868, July 30.Valentin Uhink to E.L. Plumb., A.N.S. in Spanish.
  - 20. 1868, Aug 13.Mexico City, Ayuntamiento to E.L. Plumb [R. Marj de la Forse, R. Sayago, Lucie Padilla]., L.S. in Spanish.
  - 21. 1868, Aug 14.A. Labat to [E.L. Plumb]., L.S. in Spanish.
  - 22. 1868, Aug 15.Julius A. Skilton to E.L. Plumb., A.N.S.
  - 23. 1868, Aug 18.J.A. Gadsden to E.L. Plumb, A.N.S.
  - 24. 1868, Aug 20.King, Kenedy & Co. to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 25. 1868, Aug 26.M. Romero to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 26. 1868, Sept 2.Chas. W. Davis to E.L. Plumb. A general appointed minister to Mexico., A.L.S.
  - 27. 1868, Sept 2.Juan A. Robinson to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 28. 1868, Sept 19.N. Davidson to E.L. Plumb., A.N.S.
  - 29. 1868, Sept 20.Blas. Blacarcel to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S. in Spanish.
  - 30. 1868, Sept 20.M. Romero to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 31-36. 1868, Sept 21.E.L. Plumb to S. Lerdo de Tejada, Jose Maria Iglesias, Ignacie Mariscal, Matias Romero, Ignacie Mejia, Blas Balcarcel Sept 21-25, Formal invitation; 5 formal replies in Spanish.
  - 37. 1868, Oct 1.-Dec. 10.E.L. Plumb to State Department., Statement of account
  - 38. 1868, Oct 9.S. de Mobellan to E.L. Plumb., A.N.S. in Spanish.
  - 39. 1868, Oct 22.-Dec 10.Expense account, U.S. legation in Mexico. E.L. Plumb., A.D.S.
  - 40. 1868, Oct 29.H.B. Anthony to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 41. 1868, Nov 3.E.L. Plumb to Matias Romero. Investigation of claims of Treadwell & Co. against Mexican gov't. Vega's purchase of arms. in S.F. Ochoa bonds., A.L.S.
    move to 1-7-7a.
  - 42. 1868, Nov 9.M.J. de Lizardi to E.L. Plumb., A.N.S.
  - 43. 1868, Nov 12.Thos. C. Reynolds to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 44. 1868, Nov 18.H.D.J. Pratt to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 45. 1868, Nov 25.W.S. Rosecrans to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 46. 1868, Dec 1.S. Lerdo de Tejada to E.L. Plumb., Formal invitation in Spanish.
  - 47. 1868, Dec 5.W.S. Rosecrans to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 48. 1868, Dec 9.W.S. Rosecrans to E.L. Plumb., A.N.S.
  - 49. 1868, Dec 10.E.L. Plumb to William H. Seward. Resignation., A.L.S.
  - 50. 1868, Dec 10.E.L. Plumb to State Department; bill for salary., A.N.S.
  - 51. 1868, Dec 10.E.L. Plumb; inventory of archives and property of legation of U.S. at Mexico. Signed by W.S. Rosecrans., A.D.S.
  - 52. 1868, Dec 18.E.L. Plumb. Recommendation., A.L.S.
  - 53. 1868, Dec 23.S. Lerdo de Tejada to E.L. Plumb., L.S. in Spanish.
  - 54. 1868, Dec 23.S. Lerdo de Tejada to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S. in Spanish (copy).
  - 55. 1868, Dec 23.E.L. Plumb to S. Lerdo de Tejada., A.L.S. in Spanish (copy).
  - 56. 1868, Dec 25.Luis Gutierrez to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S. in Spanish.
  - 57. 1868, Dec 25.S. Lerdo de Tejada to E.L. Plumb., L.S. in Spanish.
  - 58. 1868, Dec 25.E.L. Plumb. Recommendation., A.N.S.
  - 59. 1868, Dec 26.Manuel Payne to E.L. Plumb., A.N. in Spanish.
  - 60. 1868, Dec 26.Francisco le P. Pastor to E.L. Plumb., A.N. in Spanish.
  - 61. 1868, Dec [26].A.E. Rosecrans to E.L. Plumb., A.N.S.
  - 62. 1868, Dec 27.Lerdo de Tejada to E.L. Plumb., L.S. in Sp.
- CORRESPONDENCE 1869, January-May (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - 1. 1869, Jan 4.William H. Seward to E.L. Plumb. Acceptance of resignation., L.S.
  - 2. 1869, Jan 8.Francisco Fesser to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 3. 1869, Jan 13.and report. R.W. Taylor to E.L. Plumb., L.S.
  - 4. 1869, Jan 22.Chas. Kearney Brown to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 5. 1869, Jan 27.Adam Badeau to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 6. 1869, Jan 28.Leandro de la Cuestas to E.L. Plumb., A.L.
  - 7. 1869, Feb 5.F. von Gerolt to E.L. Plumb., A.N.S.
  - 8. 1869, Feb 5.E.L. Plumb to F.von Gerolt, A.L.S.
  - 9. 1869, Mar 3.Edw. E. Dunbar to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 10. 1869, Mar 21.Francisco Fesser to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 11. 1869, Mar 26.David Hoadley to E.L. Plumb. Plumb appointed Consul General at Havana, question of minister to Mexico., A.L.S.
  - 12. 1869, Mar 27.Antonio F. Bromozio to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S. in Spanish.
  - 13. 1869, Mar 27.James S. Mackie to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 14. 1869, Mar 28.F.von Gerolt to E.L. Plumb, A.N.S.
  - 15. 1869, Apr 14.David Hoadley to E.L. Plumb. Silas A. Hudson., A.L.S.
  - 16. 1869, Apr 15.O.E. Babcock to E.L. Plumb., A.N.S.
  - 17. 1869, Apr 16.David Hoadley to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 18. 1869, Apr 16.E.L. Plumb to William Hunter., A.L.S.
  - 19. 1869, Apr 21.E.L. Plumb et al, Bond., A.D.S. (copy).
  - 20. 1869, Apr 23.R.S. Chew to E.L. Plumb., L.S.
  - 21. 1869, Apr 26.Jasper Smith to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 22. 1869, May 3 & 4.List and copies of letters of introduction to Havana.
  - 23. 1869, May 4.Moses Taylor to Miguel Aldama., A.L.S.
  - 24. 1869, May 19.J.C. Audenreid to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 25. 1869, May 23.Matias Romero to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 26. 1869, May 23.Wm. D. Whitney to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 27. 1869, May 24.L.V. Schmidt to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 28. 1869, May 24.James H. Springer to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 29. 1869, May 24.Joseph A. Springer to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 30. 1869, May 25.A. Graham-Dunlop to E.L. Plumb., A.N.S.
  - 31. 1869, May 29.Joseph A. Raphel to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 32. 1869, May 29.Wm. Scharfenberg to E.L. Plumb., A.N.S.
- CORRESPONDENCE 1869, June-July (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - 1. 1869, June 3.George Cowie to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 2. 1869, June 3.Forbin Janson to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S. in French.
  - 3. 1869, June 3.E.L. Plumb to Forbin Janson., A.L.S.
  - 4. 1869, June 7.Dionisic Lopez Roberts to E.L. Plumb., A.N.S. in Spanish.
  - 5. 1869, June 10.A. Graham Dunlop to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 6. 1869, June 10.Henry C. Hall to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 7. 1869, June 11.E.L. Plumb to J. Edgar Thompson. U.S. coal for Spanish navy., A.L.S.
  - 8. 1869, June 12.Commodore Phillimore to E.L. Plumb., A.N.
  - 9. 1869, June 14.A.V. Kautz to E.L. Plumb. Indian trouble, the West., A.L.S.
  - 10. 1869, June 15.Henry K. Hoff to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 11. 1869, June 16.E.L. Plumb to Henry K. Hoff., A.L.S.
  - 12. 1869, June 18.partially in code. Hamilton Fish to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 13. 1869, June 22.E.L. Plumb to Henry K. Hoff. Spanish-British clash, revolt., A.L.S.
  - 14. 1869, June 22.Jasper Smith to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 15. 1869, June 25.E.L. Plumb to Henry K. Hoff., A.L.S.
  - 16. 1869, June 29.E.L. Plumb to Henry K. Hoff., A.L.S.
  - 17. 1869, July 2.S. Lordo de Tejada to E.L. Plumb., L.S. in Spanish.
  - 18. 1869, July 2.Matias Romero to E.L. Plumb. Mexican situation., A.L.S.
  - 19. 1869, July 3.R.S. Chew to E.L. Plumb., L.S.
  - 20. 1869, July 6.R.S. Chilton to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 21. 1869, July 9.Julius A. Skilton to E.L. Plumb. Mexican affairs, railroad., A.L.S.
  - 22. 1869, July 10.Ignacio Mariscal to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 23. 1869, July 10.E.L. Plumb to R.S. Chilton. Execution of Americans in Cuba., A.L.S.
  - 24. 1869, July 10.E.L. Plumb to Jasper Smith., A.L.S.
  - 25. 1869, July 19.A. Graham-Dunlop to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 26. 1869, July 22.Matias Romero to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 27. 1869, July 27.Caleb Cushing to E.L. Plumb..Cuban insurrection., A.L.S.
  - 28. 1869, July 30.Forbin Janson to E.L. Plumb., A.N.S. in French.
  - 29. 1869, July 31.E.L. Plumb to Henry K. Hoff., A.N.S.
  - 30. 1869, July.John 7. Crawford., A.N.S.
- CORRESPONDENCE 1869, August-September (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - 1. 1869, Aug 2.Antonio Caballero to E.L. Plumb., L. (transl.)
  - 2. 1869, Aug 6.R.S. Chew to E. L. Plumb., L.S.
  - 3. 1869, Aug 6.J. Russell Jones to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 4. 1869, Aug 7.E.L. Plumb to Caleb Cushing., A.L.
  - 5. 1869, Aug 7.E.L. Plumb to Charles Sumner., A.L.
  - 6. 1869, Aug 11.Henry K. Hoff to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S. & copy.
  - 7. 1869, Aug 12.E.L. Plumb to J.C. Audenreid., A.L.S.
  - 8. 1869, Aug 13.Ramsden report-Santiago de Cuba. Description of rebels, murder of prisoners.
  - 9. 1869, Aug 18.G.R. Ruthven to E.L. Plumb, A.N.S.
  - 10. 1869, Aug 19.Wm. T. Coleman to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 11. 1869, Aug 19.Ignacio Mariscal to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 12. 1869, Aug 21.J.G. Barbon to E.L. Plumb., A.N.S.
  - 13. 1869, Aug 21.E.L. Plumb to J.C. Bancroft Davis., A.L.S.
  - 14. 1869, Aug 21.E.L. Plumb to S. Lerdo de Tejada., A.L.S.
  - 15. 1869, Aug 29.Joseph C. Audenreid to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 16. 1869, Aug 29.J. Russell Jones to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 17. 1869, Sept 1.E.L. Plumb to J.C. Bancroft Davis., A.L.S.
  - 18. 1869, Sept 3.Caleb Cushing to E.L. Plumb, A.L.S.
  - 19. 1869, Sept 3.E.L. Plumb to William Hunter., A.L.S.
  - 20. 1869, Sept 4.Caleb Cushing to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 21. 1869, Sept 4.Hamilton Fish to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 22. 1869, Sept 5.Jasper Smith to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 23. 1869, Sept 10.W. Hunter to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 24. 1869, Sept 11.Joseph C. Audenreid to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 25. 1869, Sept 11.E.L. Plumb to J.C. Bancroft Davis., A.L.S.
  - 26. 1869, Sept 15.Ignacio Mariscal to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 27. 1869, Sept 16.E.L. Plumb to Hamilton Fish. Cuba and slavery., A.L.S.
  - 28. 1869, Sept 17.E.L. Plumb to Hamilton Fish., A.L.S.
  - 29. 1869, Sept 24.E.L. Plumb to J.C. Audenreid., A.L.S.
  - 30. 1869, Sept 25.George Earl Church to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 31. 1869, Sept 30.E.L. Plumb to Charles Sumner. U.S. Cuban plicy., A.L.S.
- CORRESPONDENCE 1869, October-December (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - 1. 1869, Oct 1.J. Russell Jones to E.L. Plumb., Note.
  - 2. 1869, Oct 2.E.L. Plumb to Hamilton Fish. The volunteers, independence for Cuba impractical, fillibusters, consular duty distasteful., A.L.
  - 3. 1869, Oct 4.Cesares Fernandez to E.L. Plumb., L.S. in Spanish.
  - 4. 1869, Oct 8.A.G. Curtin to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 5. 1869, Oct 8.August V. Kautz to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 6. 1869, Oct 8.E.L. Plumb to Caleb Cushing, A.L.S.
  - 7. 1869, Oct 14.R.C. McCormick to E.L. Plumb, L.S.
  - 8. 1869, Oct 25.E.L. Plumb to R.S. Chew. Wishes to resign., A.L.S.
  - 9. 1869, Oct 25.E.L. Plumb to Hamilton Fish. Private letter., A.L.S.
  - 10. 1869, Oct 25.E.L. Plumb to Hamilton Fish. Formal resignation., A.L.S.
  - 11. 1869, Oct 27.Report U.S. Treasurer to E.L. Plumb.
  - 12. 1869, Nov 3.C.H. Poor to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 13. 1869, Nov 5.J.C.B. Davis to E.L. Plumb., L. copy
  - 14. 1869, Nov 6.J.C.B. Davis to E.L. Plumb. Acceptance of resignation., L. copy
  - 15. 1869, [Nov 6]Julius A. Skilton to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 16. 1869, Nov 7.Wm. E. Dodge, Jr. to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 17. 1869, Nov 8.Maurice Delfosse to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 18. 1869, Nov 8.E.L. Plumb to Superior Political Governor of Cuba. Formal protest., D.S. (copy)
  - 19. 1869, Nov 8.C.H. Poor to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 20. 1869, Nov 13.H.C. Hall to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 21. 1869, Nov 19.O.E. Babcock to E.L. Plumb, A.L.S.
  - 22. 1869, Nov 23.Henry C. Hall to E.L. Plumb, A.L.S.
  - 23. 1869, Nov 23.Horace Porter to E.L. Plumb, A.L.S.
  - 24. 1869, Nov 24.R.S. Chilton to E.L. Plumb, A.L.S.
  - 25. 1869, Nov 25.E.L. Plumb to David Hoadley., A.L.S.
  - 26. 1869, Nov 25.E.L. Plumb to W.T. Sherman., A.L.S.
  - 27. 1869, Nov 27.Antonio Caballer to E.L. Plumb., L. copy in Spanish and Transl.
  - 28. 1869, Nov 30.D. Expenses of Plumb at Havana.
  - 29. 1869, Dec 1.Joseph Springer et al to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 30. 1869, Dec 2.E.L. Plumb to Henry C. Hall, A.L.S.
  - 31. 1869, Dec 6.E.L. Plumb to Charles H. Poor., A.L.S.
  - 32. 1869, Dec 9.Sight draft.
  - 33. 1869, Dec 9.E.L. Plumb to A.G. Curtin., A.L.S.
  - 34. 1869, Dec 9.E.L. Plumb to H.Kreismann, A.L.S.
  - 35. 1869, Dec 10,E.L. Plumb to Charles Sumner., A.L.S.
  - 36. 1869, Dec 10.E.L. Plumb to R.C. McCormick., A.L.S.
  - 37. 1869, Dec 11.E.L. Plumb to Charles H. Poor., A.L.S.
  - 38. 1869, Dec 15.E.L. Plumb to Charles Sumner., A.L.S.
  - 39. 1869, Dec 23.Matias Romero to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 40. 1869, Dec 25.E.W. Gurney to E.L. Plumb, A.L.S.
  - 41. 1869, Dec 27.Testimonial letter to Plumb signed by various companies etc. in Havana.
  - 42. 1869, Dec 29.Charles H. Poor to E.L. Plumb., L.S.
  - 43. 1869.Financial notes.
  - 44. [1869]Six months work in Havana-list.
- CORRESPONDENCE 1870 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 1. 1870, Jan 1.J. Emilio de Santos to E.L. Plumb., L.S. in Spanish and transl.
  - 2. 1870, Jan5.E.L. Plumb to Henry C. Hall, A.L.S.
  - 3. 1870, Jan 8.Henry C. Hall to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 4. 1870, Jan 12.E.L. Plumb to H.C. Hall., A.L.S.
  - 5. 1870, Jan 12.E.L. Plumb to H.C. Hall., A.L.S.
  - 6. 1870, Jan 22.Henry C. Hall to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 7. 1870, Jan 28.Henry C. Hall to E.L. Plumb, A.L.S.
  - 8. 1870, Jan 31.E.L. Plumb to Jose Garcia Barbon. Introducing Thomas Biddle., A.L.S.
  - 9. 1870, Jan 31.E.L. Plumb to Henry C. Hall., A.L.S.
  - 10. 1870, Feb 1.E.L. Plumb to Henry C. Hall., A.L.S.
  - 11. 1870, Feb 3.James S. Mackie to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 12. 1870, Feb 7.E.L. Plumb to James S. Mackie., A.L.S.
  - 13. 1870, Feb 9.Thomas Biddle to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 14. 1870, Feb 9.E.L. Plumb to E.W. Gurney., A.L.S.
  - 15. 1870, Feb 12.Henry C. Hall to E.L. Plumb. Cuban situation worse., A.L.S.
  - 16. 1870, Feb 15.J.H. Plumb to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 17. 1870, Feb 18.Jose Antonio Fesser to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 18. 1870, Feb 19.Henry C. Hall to E.L. Plumb, A.L.S.
  - 19. 1870, Feb 26.Chas. Collins to E.L. Plumb, A.L.S.
  - 20. 1870, Mar 8.Ellen B.E. Sherman to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 21. 1870, Mar 12.Adam Badeau to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 22. 1870, Mar 21.E.L. Plumb to James S. Mackie., A.L.S.
  - 23. 1870, Mar 23.R.W. Taylor to E.L. Plumb., L.S.
  - 24. 1870, Mar 24.Thomas Biddle to E.L. Plumb, A.L.S.
  - 25. 1870, Apr 15.E.L. Plumb to Thomas Biddle., A.L.S.
  - 26. 1870, Apr 22.Henry C. Hall to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 27. 1870, Apr 25.R.C. McCormick to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 28. 1870, May 3.John W. Forney to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 29. 1870, May 3.H.A. Johnson & Co. to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 30. 1870, May 9.E.L. Plumb to Matias Romero., A.L.S.
  - 31. 1870, June 2.Thomas Biddle to E.L. Plumb. Cuban policy of U.S., A.L.S.
  - 32. 1870, June 2.Grace S. Bristed to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 33. 1870, June 3.Henry C. Hall to E.L. Plumb. Ship Lloyd Aspinwall., A.L.S.
  - 34. 1870, June 16.E.L. Plumb to Mrs. Bristed., A.L.S.
  - 35. 1870, June 19.Forbin Janson to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S. in French.
- CORRESPONDENCE 1870, July-September (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - 1. 1870, July 4.Elijah Ward to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 2. 1870, July 5.E.L. Plumb to Thomas Biddle., A.L.S.
  - 3. 1870, July 5.E.L. Plumb to Henry C. Hall., A.L.S.
  - 4. 1870, July 8.Henry C. Hall to E.L. Plumb. Slavery question on Cuba., A.L.S.
  - 5. 1870, July 19.E.L. Plumb to H.C. Hall. War in Europe., A.L.S.
  - 6. 1870, July 29.Henry C. Hall to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 7. 1870, July. Commercial relations with the Spanish American States. July 7, Fenton's Resolution; July 14, Report of Dept. of State, statistics, drafts, extracts, reprint, notes., clips
  - 8. 1870, Aug 5.E.L. Plumb to R.S. Chew., A.L.S.
  - 9. 1870, Sept 1.R.S. Chew to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 10-12. 1870.Population and area statistics of U.S.
- CORRESPONDENCE 1871. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 1. 1871, Jan 14.Charles D. Poston to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 2. [1871,], Feb 1.Henry C. Hall to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 3. 1871, Mar 3.J.R. West to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 4. 1871, Apr 19.Henry K.Hoff to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 5. 1871, Apr 27.John N. Goodwin to E.L. Plumb. Northern Pacific Railroad., A.L.S.
  - 6. 1871, May 20.E.L. Plumb to R.E. Fenton. Treaty of Washington., A.L.S.
  - 7. 1871, May 23.Whitelaw Reid to E.L. Plumb., L.
  - 8. 1871, June 5.George E. Church to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 9. 1871, June 7.[S.B. Ruffly] to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.
  - 10. 1871, June 8.E.L. Plumb. to A.L. Lee., A.L.S.
  - 11. 1871, June 15.E.L. Plumb to J.C. Bancroft Davis. Ratification of Washington treaty., A.L.S.
  - 12. 1871, June 16.J.C. Bancroft Davis to E.L. Plumb., A.L.S.